Teague Stockwell

Seattle, WA

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Software engineer and transitioning service member with 4 years of experience in the US Air Force. Demonstrated proficiency and ownership of the full software development lifecycle to solve complex business problems like aircraft cargo loading. A passionate and consistent full stack developer that is quick to adapt and master the latest technology.

SKILLS

Languages Typescript, JavaScript, Dart, Java

Frontend React, React Query, State Mgmt libs, HTML, CSS, Flutter, Android

Backend Next, Prisma(ORM), Express, Node

Services PostgreSQL, Firebase, Vercel, AWS(RDS, S3, EC2), Nginx Workflow CI / CD, Docker, TDD, GitHub, GitLab, Git, JWT, Jira

EXPERIENCE

Rainier Spark Tron | Lead Software Engineer

JBLM, WA | June 2021 - Present

- Deployed aircraft cargo management app to user base of over 2k that reduced weight and balance times 93%
- Pioneered agile software innovation cell by mentoring new developers to promote diversity and inclusion

Aloha Spark Tron | Software Engineer

Remote | Nov 2020 – June 2021

- Implemented 120 user stories while maintaining 2 CI pipelines with a total of 34 stages
- Leveraged CI/CD and DevOps to accredit and deploy a production app in < 5 months to a secure government cloud
- Wrote Mocha, Jest, React Testing Lib and Cypress tests for 2 services to increase line coverage to 80%

US Air Force | Aerospace Mechanic

JBLM, WA | Oct 2017 - Oct 2020

• Lead & perform repairs / inspections on 20 assigned C-17 aircraft valued at \$3.2B

PROJECTS

Buildable – Social Media Platform | Code | Live App

PostgreSQL | Next | React | Node | AWS (S3, CloudFront, RDS), OAuth 2.0

- · Created post interaction with subreddits, threaded comments, likes, saves, rich text editing and mentions
- · Implemented a serverless REST API to manage pre signed image uploads and user roles

Levels V3 – Aircraft Cargo Loading | UI Code | API Code | Demo

PostgreSQL | Express | React | Node | Node | Docker

- · Created a React UI that subscribes to server updates and caches them to enable offline persistence
- · Developed an API for JWT based user roles and to sync pending updates between clients in near real time

Five Level V2 – Aircraft Cargo Loading | UI Code | API Code | Live App

Firebase | Express | Node | Flutter | Docker

- · Modified Docker imgs to create a CI /CD Pipeline for static code analysis, linting and testing to harden app security
- Fetched data from a NoSQL Document DB (Firebase) and displayed a cargo loading UI with offline persistence

EDUCATION

Southwestern College | B.S. Computer Programming Community College of the Air Force | A.A.S. Aviation Maintenance Aug 2019 – May 2021 Oct 2017 – Aug 2019